Leisure rules.
Ferris Bueller's Day Off is a comedy film directed by John Hughes.
After high school slacker Ferris Bueller successfully fakes an illness in order to skip school for the day, he goes on a series of adventures throughout
Chicago with his girlfriend Sloane and best friend Cameron, all the while trying to outwit his wily school principal and fed-up sister.
Ferris Bueller, played by Matthew Broderick.
Cameron Frye, played by Alan Ruck.
Sloane Peterson, played by Mia Sara.
Ed Rooney, played by Jeffrey Jones.
Jeanie Bueller, played by Jennifer Grey.
Katie Bueller, played by Cindy Pickett.
Ferris Bueller's Day Off is a 1986 American teen comedy film
written, co-produced, and directed by John Hughes.
The film stars Matthew Broderick, Mia Sara, and Alan Ruck, with supporting roles from Jennifer
Grey, Jeffrey Jones, Cindy Pickett, Edie McClurg, Lyman Ward and Charlie Sheen.
It tells the story of the eponymous character, a charismatic high school slacker who lives in Chicago and skips school with his best friend
Cameron and his girlfriend Sloane for a day, regularly breaking the fourth wall to explain his techniques and inner thoughts.
Hughes wrote the screenplay in less than a week.
Filming began in September 1985 and finished in November, featuring many Chicago landmarks
including the Sears Tower, Wrigley Field, and the Art Institute of Chicago.
The film was Hughes's love letter to Chicago: "I really
wanted to capture as much of Chicago as I could.
Not just in the architecture and landscape, but the spirit."
Released by Paramount Pictures on June 11, 1986, the film became
the tenth-highest-grossing film of 1986 in the United States, grossing $70.7 million over a $5 million budget.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and audiences alike, who
praised Broderick's performance, and the film's humor and tone.
In 2014, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress, being deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film was followed by a television series, starring
Charlie Schlatter as the title character.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, high
school, independence, coming of age, caper.
The tone is lighthearted.